Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
In that paulownia wood case was a mummified left paw.
（阿良々木(あららぎ)）
桐(きり)の箱に入った左手のミイラ
REMINISCENCE
Suruga, grade school student.
Animation Number 9
Kanbaru received it from her late mother, and the first time she used it was in fourth grade.
神原(かんばる)が亡き母から
託された それを
初めて使ったのは
小学４年生の
ときだったという
I want to run fast.
Animation Number 11
（神原）
足が速くなりたいです
Kanbaru had just transferred to a new school after her parents' deaths, but she didn't fit in with her new class
（阿良々木）
そのころ両親が亡くなって
転校したばかりの神原は
クラスになじめず また
足が遅かったこともあって
and was often teased for being a slow runner.
よく からかわれていた
She thought that maybe if she got first place at the athletic meet that was going on nearby,
そこで 近く行われる運動会の
徒競走で１等を取れば
everyone would see her in a different light.
みんなの自分を見る目も
変わるんじゃないか
With that in mind, she made her wish.
そう思っての願いだったそうだ
That night.
Animation Number 15
Kanbaru had a horrible dream.
Surveillance camera
Animation Number 17
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Animation Number 19
A monster attacked the four other students who were in the race with Kanbaru.
化け物に
襲われていたのは
神原が
徒競走で一緒に走る
４人の生徒たちだった
Classroom, view from above.
The next day, all four of them were absent.
翌日 その生徒たちは
そろって欠席したそうだ
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
On-the-spot filming
Animation number 21
Kanbaru soon found Jacobs's "The Monkey's Paw",
神原は すぐにジェイコブズの
「猿の手」に行き当たった
and the terrifying contents of the story made her tremble.
そして その内容の恐ろしさに
背が震えたそうだ
In the worst case
Animation Number 23
Those four might have already been dead.
Animation number 25
Death
Animation Number 26
Thinking about it normally, in order to cancel the first wish, she'd have to wish on the mummified paw again.
普通に考えれば１つ目の願いを
キャンセルしたいと
ミイラに願うしかないだろう
But after researching the mummy, she grew scared,
けれど ミイラのことを調べていた
神原には それが怖かった
because she didn't know how the second wish would be granted.
２つ目の願いが どのような形で
かなえられてしまうか
分かったものでは ないからだ
その翌日
Next day
Animation Number 28
The next day at practice,
it turned out that she would be running with five other students, all different from the last.
徒競走の練習の際に
神原は前の４人とは別の
５人の生徒たちと
一緒に走ることになった
Animation Number 31
So I ran. I poured my heart into getting faster.
（神原）
だから 私は走った
速くなるための努力をした
It was plain as day that if I didn't do something, something else might happen.
そのまま何もしないでいたら
何が起こるかは
火を見るより明らかだった
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
REMINISCENCE
Kanbaru didn't join the track team.
（阿良々木）
神原は
陸上部に入らなかった
Suruga, grade school student.
Animation Number 38
Not knowing how long her wish on the Monkey's Paw would be effective,
猿の手に願った願いが
いつまで効力を持っているか
分からない以上
she couldn't put herself in a situation where there could be people faster than her.
自分より速いかもしれない人間が
いるところに
身を置くわけには
いかなかったからだ
So, Kanbaru...
Animation Number 40
Joined the basketball team.
Neither on court nor on the field
Animation Number 43
nobody could ever
Animation Number 45
match Kanbaru.
Animation Number 47
In no time, Kanbaru...
Animation Number 50
Became the ace of the basketball team.
One day after hearing about my reputation, Senjougahara-senpai came to the gym.
ある日 私の評判を聞いて
戦場ヶ原(せんじょうがはら)先輩が
体育館にやって来た
She was the track team's ace, so she came to see me since I had a reputation for being fast.
戦場ヶ原先輩は
陸上部のエースだったから
足が速いと評判の私を
見に来てくれたんだ
She challenged me to a 100-meter race, saying it was fine since it was off the record.
そして 非公式でいいから
100メートル走をしようと誘われた
Though it was really hard, I had no choice but to turn her down.
それを断らざるをえなかったのは
本当に つらかったな
She was a wonderful upperclassman.
Animation Number 58
すてきな先輩だった
It wasn't love at first sight, but after talking with her for three days, I started liking her.
一目ぼれこそは しなかったが
話すようになって３日目には
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
もう戦場ヶ原先輩のことを
好きになっていた
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
I was healed by Senjougahara-senpai.
私は戦場ヶ原先輩に
癒されていたのだ
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
After that, Kanbaru was able to stop thinking about the mummified paw.
（阿良々木）
それから神原はミイラのことを
意識から外せるようになったらしい
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Still...
Animation Number 65
But even still, she would occasionally feel an urge to use it...
だが それでも
発作的にミイラを
使ってしまいたい
という衝動に
駆られることはあった
When she played against a fierce rival in basketball.
バスケットボールの試合で
強豪に当たったとき
When she had heated arguments with friends.
友達と ひどいケンカをしたとき
そして
And...
When I was rejected by Senjougahara-senpai.
戦場ヶ原先輩に拒絶されたとき
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
In the end, I didn't use it.
結局 ミイラを
使ったことはなかった
It was then that I came to understand that my mother gave me the mummified paw
そのころには お母さんが私に
ミイラを託したのは
because she wanted me to become the type of person who could overcome any obstacle with my own strength.
困難に遭っても自分の力だけで
対処できる人間になってほしいと
思っていたからだと
分かっていたからだ
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
That's why Kanbaru shut up and distanced herself from Senjougahara.
（神原･
阿良々木･戦場ヶ原）
だから 神原は
黙って
戦場ヶ原から身を引いた
She may have been able to solve Senjougahara's problem by wishing on the paw, but she didn't.
ミイラに願えば 当時
戦場ヶ原が抱えていた秘密を
解決することが
できたかもしれないけれど
それも しなかった
But a year later, Kanbaru found out about me.
でも その１年後…
（阿良々木）
神原は僕のことを知ってしまった
She saw me at Senjougahara's side.
戦場ヶ原のそばにいる僕を
見てしまった
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Animation Number 81
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Kanbaru no longer knows when she took the paw out of the paulownia wood box.
（神原･阿良々木･戦場ヶ原）
いつ桐箱から
ミイラを取り出したのか
神原には もう分からないそうだ
It never even occurred to her why the paw,
そして 左手首までしか
なかったはずのミイラが
which should have only extended to the wrist, had grown all the way to the elbow.
どうして肘の部分まで
伸びてしまっているのか
ということにすら
全く考えが及ばず
And before she knew,
Animation Number 86
そして 気が付けば…
Kanbaru's left hand had...
Animation Number 88
...already become a spirit.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
END OF THE REMINISCENCE
Next is the theme song
Rainy Devil is said to be a very violent devil.
Above all it loves people's anger and hostility,
grievance and repentance, envy and jealousy,
all the dark traits and negative emotions.
Above all it loves people's anger and hostility,
grievance and repentance, envy and jealousy,
all the dark traits and negative emotions.
Above all it loves people's anger and hostility,
grievance and repentance, envy and jealousy,
all the dark traits and negative emotions.
Above all it loves people's anger and hostility,
grievance and repentance, envy and jealousy,
all the dark traits and negative emotions.
Above all it loves people's anger and hostility,
grievance and repentance, envy and jealousy,
all the dark traits and negative emotions.
Above all it loves people's anger and hostility,
grievance and repentance, envy and jealousy,
all the dark traits and negative emotions.
Above all it loves people's anger and hostility,
grievance and repentance, envy and jealousy,
all the dark traits and negative emotions.
Above all it loves people's anger and hostility,
grievance and repentance, envy and jealousy,
all the dark traits and negative emotions.
Above all it loves people's anger and hostility,
grievance and repentance, envy and jealousy,
all the dark traits and negative emotions.
Above all it loves people's anger and hostility,
grievance and repentance, envy and jealousy,
all the dark traits and negative emotions.
Above all it loves people's anger and hostility,
grievance and repentance, envy and jealousy,
all the dark traits and negative emotions.
Above all it loves people's anger and hostility,
grievance and repentance, envy and jealousy,
all the dark traits and negative emotions.
Above all it loves people's anger and hostility,
grievance and repentance, envy and jealousy,
all the dark traits and negative emotions.
Above all it loves people's anger and hostility,
grievance and repentance, envy and jealousy,
all the dark traits and negative emotions.
Above all it loves people's anger and hostility,
grievance and repentance, envy and jealousy,
all the dark traits and negative emotions.
Above all it loves people's anger and hostility,
grievance and repentance, envy and jealousy,
all the dark traits and negative emotions.
Above all it loves people's anger and hostility,
grievance and repentance, envy and jealousy,
all the dark traits and negative emotions.
Above all it loves people's anger and hostility,
grievance and repentance, envy and jealousy,
all the dark traits and negative emotions.
Above all it loves people's anger and hostility,
grievance and repentance, envy and jealousy,
all the dark traits and negative emotions.
Above all it loves people's anger and hostility,
grievance and repentance, envy and jealousy,
all the dark traits and negative emotions.
Above all it loves people's anger and hostility,
grievance and repentance, envy and jealousy,
all the dark traits and negative emotions.
Above all it loves people's anger and hostility,
grievance and repentance, envy and jealousy,
all the dark traits and negative emotions.
Above all it loves people's anger and hostility,
grievance and repentance, envy and jealousy,
all the dark traits and negative emotions.
It sees through all the dark sides of the human, provokes them,
pulls them out and lets them manifest themselves. It listens to
wishes in a malevolent way and fulfills them in a malevolent way.
It sees through all the dark sides of the human, provokes them,
pulls them out and lets them manifest themselves. It listens to
wishes in a malevolent way and fulfills them in a malevolent way.
It sees through all the dark sides of the human, provokes them,
pulls them out and lets them manifest themselves. It listens to
wishes in a malevolent way and fulfills them in a malevolent way.
It sees through all the dark sides of the human, provokes them,
pulls them out and lets them manifest themselves. It listens to
wishes in a malevolent way and fulfills them in a malevolent way.
It sees through all the dark sides of the human, provokes them,
pulls them out and lets them manifest themselves. It listens to
wishes in a malevolent way and fulfills them in a malevolent way.
It sees through all the dark sides of the human, provokes them,
pulls them out and lets them manifest themselves. It listens to
wishes in a malevolent way and fulfills them in a malevolent way.
It sees through all the dark sides of the human, provokes them,
pulls them out and lets them manifest themselves. It listens to
wishes in a malevolent way and fulfills them in a malevolent way.
It sees through all the dark sides of the human, provokes them,
pulls them out and lets them manifest themselves. It listens to
wishes in a malevolent way and fulfills them in a malevolent way.
It sees through all the dark sides of the human, provokes them,
pulls them out and lets them manifest themselves. It listens to
wishes in a malevolent way and fulfills them in a malevolent way.
It sees through all the dark sides of the human, provokes them,
pulls them out and lets them manifest themselves. It listens to
wishes in a malevolent way and fulfills them in a malevolent way.
It sees through all the dark sides of the human, provokes them,
pulls them out and lets them manifest themselves. It listens to
wishes in a malevolent way and fulfills them in a malevolent way.
It sees through all the dark sides of the human, provokes them,
pulls them out and lets them manifest themselves. It listens to
wishes in a malevolent way and fulfills them in a malevolent way.
It sees through all the dark sides of the human, provokes them,
pulls them out and lets them manifest themselves. It listens to
wishes in a malevolent way and fulfills them in a malevolent way.
It sees through all the dark sides of the human, provokes them,
pulls them out and lets them manifest themselves. It listens to
wishes in a malevolent way and fulfills them in a malevolent way.
It sees through all the dark sides of the human, provokes them,
pulls them out and lets them manifest themselves. It listens to
wishes in a malevolent way and fulfills them in a malevolent way.
It sees through all the dark sides of the human, provokes them,
pulls them out and lets them manifest themselves. It listens to
wishes in a malevolent way and fulfills them in a malevolent way.
It sees through all the dark sides of the human, provokes them,
pulls them out and lets them manifest themselves. It listens to
wishes in a malevolent way and fulfills them in a malevolent way.
It sees through all the dark sides of the human, provokes them,
pulls them out and lets them manifest themselves. It listens to
wishes in a malevolent way and fulfills them in a malevolent way.
It sees through all the dark sides of the human, provokes them,
pulls them out and lets them manifest themselves. It listens to
wishes in a malevolent way and fulfills them in a malevolent way.
As for the contract,
the contract itself is that...
In exchange for the human's soul, it fulfills three wishes.
After fulfilling those three wishes,
it captures the human's body and soul.
In other words,
in the end the human turns
into a devil, that's the result.
If Kanbaru had...
made a wish to solve the situation
when she found out
Senjougahara's secret a year ago,
that wish wouldn't have been granted.
when she found out
Senjougahara's secret a year ago,
that wish wouldn't have been granted.
when she found out
Senjougahara's secret a year ago,
that wish wouldn't have been granted.
when she found out
Senjougahara's secret a year ago,
that wish wouldn't have been granted.
when she found out
Senjougahara's secret a year ago,
that wish wouldn't have been granted.
when she found out
Senjougahara's secret a year ago,
that wish wouldn't have been granted.
when she found out
Senjougahara's secret a year ago,
that wish wouldn't have been granted.
when she found out
Senjougahara's secret a year ago,
that wish wouldn't have been granted.
The Rainy Devil can fulfill only the negative, aggressive wishes.
The devil sees
the backside of the wish.
While there's a front side, there's a backside too.
She asked to have quick legs,
because she hated her classmates.
She asked to be by Senjougahara's side
because she hated Koyomi Araragi.
She asked to have quick legs,
because she hated her classmates.
She asked to be by Senjougahara's side
because she hated Koyomi Araragi.
She asked to have quick legs,
because she hated her classmates.
She asked to be by Senjougahara's side
because she hated Koyomi Araragi.
She asked to have quick legs,
because she hated her classmates.
She asked to be by Senjougahara's side
because she hated Koyomi Araragi.
She asked to have quick legs,
because she hated her classmates.
She asked to be by Senjougahara's side
because she hated Koyomi Araragi.
Expel
Destroy
Indeed, it reads the backside.
Indeed, it sees the backside.
The devil perceives the thing
wished unconsciously.
Indeed, it reads the backside.
Indeed, it sees the backside.
The devil perceives the thing
wished unconsciously.
Indeed, it reads the backside.
Indeed, it sees the backside.
The devil perceives the thing
wished unconsciously.
Indeed, it reads the backside.
Indeed, it sees the backside.
The devil perceives the thing
wished unconsciously.
Indeed, it reads the backside.
Indeed, it sees the backside.
The devil perceives the thing
wished unconsciously.
Indeed, it reads the backside.
Indeed, it sees the backside.
The devil perceives the thing
wished unconsciously.
Indeed, it reads the backside.
Indeed, it sees the backside.
The devil perceives the thing
wished unconsciously.
Indeed, it reads the backside.
Indeed, it sees the backside.
The devil perceives the thing
wished unconsciously.
Indeed, it reads the backside.
Indeed, it sees the backside.
The devil perceives the thing
wished unconsciously.
Indeed, it reads the backside.
Indeed, it sees the backside.
The devil perceives the thing
wished unconsciously.
Indeed, it reads the backside.
Indeed, it sees the backside.
The devil perceives the thing
wished unconsciously.
Indeed, it reads the backside.
Indeed, it sees the backside.
The devil perceives the thing
wished unconsciously.
Indeed, it reads the backside.
Indeed, it sees the backside.
The devil perceives the thing
wished unconsciously.
Indeed, it reads the backside.
Indeed, it sees the backside.
The devil perceives the thing
wished unconsciously.
Indeed, it reads the backside.
Indeed, it sees the backside.
The devil perceives the thing
wished unconsciously.
Indeed, it reads the backside.
Indeed, it sees the backside.
The devil perceives the thing
wished unconsciously.
Indeed, it reads the backside.
Indeed, it sees the backside.
The devil perceives the thing
wished unconsciously.
Indeed, it reads the backside.
Indeed, it sees the backside.
The devil perceives the thing
wished unconsciously.
Indeed, it reads the backside.
Indeed, it sees the backside.
The devil perceives the thing
wished unconsciously.
Typeface used for images: HGP mincho B
Suruga Monkey,
Part Three
Episode 8
（忍野(おしの)）フッ
Araragi-kun,
阿良々木くん それに お嬢ちゃん
young lady...
Now that I understand the whole situation, what's the plan?
話は全部 分かった
それで これからどうしようって
腹積もりなんだい？
The plan?
（阿良々木）どうしようって…
Come on, Araragi-kun. I'm a pretty good specialist.
（忍野）
いや 阿良々木くん
僕は いっぱしの専門家だからね
I'm more than willing to pretend to be a half-assed authority and help you out of this situation.
半可通の なんちゃって
オーソリティーとして
こういう事態にあたって
力を貸すことには
やぶさかでは ないんだよ
W-Will you save me?
（神原）た… 助けてくれるのか
I won't save you. I'll only lend you a hand.
助けないよ　力を貸すだけ
The only one who can save you is you yourself, young lady.
君が１人で勝手に助かるだけだよ
お嬢ちゃん
But really, Araragi-kun, what am I supposed to do?
（忍野）でもね 阿良々木くん
この場合 僕は
何をすればいいのかな？
Oshino...
（阿良々木）おい 忍野
I mean, what am I supposed to do to help out this time, Araragi-kun?
つまり 今回 僕は 一体
何を手伝えばいいのか
ということなんだよ 阿良々木くん
First and foremost, there are two simple ways to handle this phenomenon.
今 起きている現象を
簡単に解決する方法は
とりあえず ２つあるよ
One is to let the Rainy Devil kill you, Araragi-kun.
１つは 阿良々木くんが
レイニー･デビルに殺されること
Koyomi Araragi
The other is...
もう１つは
to simply cut off that monstrous left arm.
その けだものの左腕を
スパッと切り落とすことさ
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Cut
left
hand
Cut
left
hand
Cut
left
hand
Cut
left
hand
Cut
left
hand
Cut
left
hand
Cut
left
hand
Cut
left
hand
Cut
left
hand
Cut
left
hand
C-Cut it off? Can you just cut off the demon parts?
（阿良々木）き… 切り落とすって
悪魔の部分だけを
切り落とせるのか？
Will her normal arm grow back afterward?
そのあとから元の腕が
生えてくるとか
It's not a lizard's tail, you know.
トカゲの尻尾でも あるまいし
Nothing's that convenient, wouldn't you agree?
そんな都合のいいこと
あるわけないじゃん
What I'm saying is that an arm is a small price to pay for this.
たかだか腕一本で
状況が解決するなら
買い物としては
安かろうってことさ
That's great and all, but it'd be pretty inconvenient for me.
それは いくらなんでも
私としても困るというか
You're trying to kill someone. Isn't that a fair price?
人間一人 殺そうとしてんだぜ？
それくらい当然の
代償じゃないのかい？
I get what you're trying to say, but hold on, Oshino!
（阿良々木）
言いたいことは分かるけれど
でも ちょっと待てよ 忍野
Killing someone isn't what Kanbaru wished for.
人間一人 殺そうとしてるって
それは神原の
望んだことじゃないんだ
Kanbaru just wants to be at Senjougahara's-
神原は ただ
戦場ヶ原の そばに…
"Just wants to be at her side?" Don't make me laugh.
（忍野）
そばに いたいだけ？ 笑うねえ
You sure are nice, Araragi-kun.
阿良々木くんは
ホントに優しいよね
So nice it makes me sick.
優しくて 胸がむかつくねえ
You seriously believe her mushy crap of an excuse, "I just want to be by her side?"
本当に もう
そばにいたいだけだなんて
そんな甘ったるい言葉を
そのまま信じたのかい？
う… 違うってのかよ
Are you saying... that's not it?
Don't you find it strange, Araragi-kun?
阿良々木くん
おかしいとは思わないのかい？
Why do you think it is that when she was in elementary school, her left hand didn't make her faster,
小学生のとき
どうして その左手は
お嬢ちゃんの足を速くせず
but instead did something like beating up those around her?
周囲をぶちのめすなんて行動に
出ちまったんだと思う？
Well... doesn't the Monkey's Paw grant wishes in a way that conflicts with the owner's intentions?
（阿良々木）
そりゃ だから 猿の手は
持ち主の意に添わない形で
願いをかなえるから…
Oshino's line
Animation Number 130
But it isn't the Monkey's Paw.
（忍野）
でも 猿の手じゃない
The Rainy Devil is a lesser demon, but a contract is a contract.
（忍野）
レイニー･デビルは
低級悪魔だけれど
契約は契約さ
If she wished to be faster, normally she would just get faster.
足が速くなりたいと願ったのなら
普通は そのまんま
足が速くなるはずだ
Does beating down her classmates make her faster?
同級生をぶちのめして
それで足が速くなるのかい？
Don't you find that rather strange?
おかしいとは思わないのかい？
Then why?
じゃあ どうしてなんだよ
Why did a monster in a raincoat come after her classmates?
雨がっぱの化け物は
どうして同級生を…
I'd bet that's because the young lady wanted to beat them up.
お嬢ちゃんが同級生を
ぶちのめしたかったからだろ
She was having a hard time just after her parents died,
（忍野）
両親が死んだばかりで
つらかった時期に
and she was being bullied by her classmates,
同級生から迫害を受けたりしたら
so it's not very strange for her to have thoughts of revenge.
復讐(ふくしゅう)を考えたとしても
全く おかしくはない
私は…
I...
Of course, I think you were unconscious when you wished for that.
（忍野）
もちろん そんなことを願ったのは
無意識のうちだったんだとは思うぜ
In your own consciousness, you really did wish to be faster.
本人の自覚としては足が
速くなりたいと願ったに違いない
But that's just the surface; deep inside is different.
だが それは表で 裏は違う
Hidden beneath your wish was the dark desire to beat up your classmates.
その願いの裏には同級生を
ぶちのめしてやりたいという
暗い願望があったのさ
Though it was unconscious, young lady, I think you should've known very well what really happened.
そして 無意識とはいえ
お嬢ちゃんには本当のところは
分かっていたはずなんだぜ
But you didn't want to admit it, so you went looking for a different explanation for what happened.
けれど 自分で認めたくないから
その現象に別の解釈を求めた
That was... the Monkey's Paw!
それが“猿の手”
Monkey's Paw.
Animation Number 142
Blaming the assault of your classmates on the Monkey's Paw distorting your wish,
同級生を襲うという
意に添わぬ形で
願いが かなったのは
猿の手のせいで
or claiming that it wasn't what you intended, is just an excuse.
あくまで自分の意思じゃないという
精神的言い訳
But Oshino...
でも 忍野…
Are you wondering what real proof I have that lets me say that, Araragi-kun?
何の確証があって
そんなことを言うんだって
思うかい 阿良々木くん
Isn't it obvious when you listen to her story?
そんなの話を聞けば
瞭然じゃないか
What happened to that arm of yours when you were in elementary school, young lady?
お嬢ちゃんの その腕
小学生のときは
どうなっていたんだい？
（阿良々木）あ…
You didn't realize it until the next day, when you went to class
（忍野）
お嬢ちゃんは次の日 教室に行って
４人の欠席を知るまで
and only those four seats were empty, isn't that right?
事が起きていることには
気付かなかったんだろ？
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
If, at that time, your left arm had ended up like it is now,
もし お嬢ちゃんの左手が
今みたいな
毛むくじゃらになっていたら
you probably would've realized something had happened.
何かが起きていることくらいには
気付くはずなのに
But you didn't include anything of that sort in your story, did you?
でも さっきの話に
そんな話は出てこなかったよね？
Which means that the aberration came one night without you noticing,
つまり 怪異(かいい)は一晩
お嬢ちゃんが気付かないうちに
お嬢ちゃんの左手に同化して
同級生をぶちのめし
latched itself onto your arm, and beat up your classmates, fulfilling your wish.
お嬢ちゃんの願いをかなえたんだ
And without you noticing, the aberration separated from your arm and left.
そして 怪異は
お嬢ちゃんが気付かないうちに
お嬢ちゃんの左手から
離れたんだろう
It probably grew from a hand to an arm
左手首が左腕になったのは
using a portion of your soul that was taken in exchange for granting your wish.
願いをかなえて得た
その魂の分だけ
成長したってことだろうさ
Hey, Oshino, that means...
て… おい 忍野 それじゃあ…
Believing the attacker's excuse, you really are a nice person, Araragi-kun.
加害者の言い訳を信じるなんて
本当に人がいいよねえ
阿良々木くんは
It's not surprising that she'd be jealous enough
大好きな先輩を寝取った男
to want to kill the guy who took away her beloved senpai.
殺したいくらいに嫉妬したとしても
おかしくはないだろうさ
When she attacked you, it wasn't against her intentions.
阿良々木くんの襲撃は
お嬢ちゃんの意に
添わぬものだったんじゃない
She intended to attack you.
阿良々木くんを襲撃することこそが
お嬢ちゃんの意思だったのさ
NEXT ARE COMMERCIALS
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（阿良々木）
ん… そろそろだろ
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
It's about time.
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（阿良々木）ん？
おっ 待ちかねたよ 阿良々木くん
I've been waiting.
Took you longer than expected.
思ったより時間が
かかったみたいだね
Yeah, I don't really know how much is too much...
（阿良々木）
ああ ちょっと ぎりぎりの基準が
分かりにくかったからさ
It might not even be enough.
少し足りないかもしれないけど
But this way's better than having her take too much.
でも 飲ませ過ぎるよりは
いいだろ
Both for me... and for Shinobu.
僕にとっても忍(しのぶ)にとっても
Since you're about to have a big fight with a demon, Araragi-kun,
阿良々木くんは これから悪魔と
くんずほぐれつの大立ち回りを
演じなくちゃならないんだからさ
I'd say it's not the best time to be thinking too much like that.
そんな 気を
回している場合じゃないと思うぜ
You're really close to your limit, but I still don't think you have a good chance of winning.
すれすれまで引き出したところで
そんな勝率の高い勝負でもないと
思うぜ
Even if your opponent is only going to use her left arm.
いくら相手は
左腕だけだとはいってもさ
A contract, huh?
（阿良々木）
契約か…
それで悪魔が おとなしく
It's fine as long as the demon just goes back to the spirit world afterward.
魔界だかに帰ってくれれば
いいんだけどな
It'll be fine. I can at least guarantee that much.
大丈夫だよ
それくらいは保証してあげる
If the contract can't be fulfilled, then it becomes void, got it?
いいかい 阿良々木くん
契約は果たせなければ無効になる
It also becomes void if the demon can't grant the young lady's wish.
悪魔が お嬢ちゃんの願いを
かなえられなければ
お嬢ちゃんの願いも無効になるさ
So basically, if I'm not killed by the devil, huh?
つまり 僕が悪魔に
殺されなければ… か
Exactly.
そういうこと
Of course, even if you power up by giving Shinobu-chan as much of your blood as you can,
もちろん 今の阿良々木くんが
今の忍ちゃんに
限界まで血を与えて
パワーアップしたとしても
Compared to during spring break when you were still a vampire,
阿良々木くんが吸血鬼だった
春休みのころの
I don't think you can draw forth more than a tenth of the power you did then.
十分の一くらいの能力しか
発揮できないと思うよ
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（阿良々木）ん… 随分な数字だな
That's quite the number.
Even so, you can't just borrow Shinobu-chan.
だからって 忍ちゃん本人の力を
借りようとしたらダメだよ
If you do, it'll be more than just a bluff... We really will have to chop off the young lady's arm.
そうなると 脅しじゃなく
本当に お嬢ちゃんの腕を
切り落とすしかなくなる
Exterminating it means something because you're doing it.
阿良々木くんが退治するから
意味を持つんだから
I'll keep an eye on your bag and valuables, Araragi-kun.
ああ かばんとか貴重品とかは
預かっといてあげるよ
阿良々木くん
It'll be hard to move if you're carrying them, won't it?
そんなもの持ったままじゃ
動きにくいだろう
（阿良々木）ん… 悪いな
Thanks.
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Okay, hold on a second.
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
じゃ
ちょっと待ってくれ
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Well then
Animation Number 202
Could you tell me one thing, Araragi-kun?
１つだけいいかい？ 阿良々木くん
What is it?
何だよ
Why do you want to save someone who tried to kill you?
どうして自分を
殺そうとした相手まで
阿良々木くんは
助けようとするんだい？
Even if it was unconsciously, that young lady chose you as her hated rival in love.
あの お嬢ちゃんは無意識とはいえ
阿良々木くんのことを
憎むべき恋敵として
捉えていたんだぜ
When you realized it was her in the raincoat, why did you decide to talk to her about it?
そもそも 雨がっぱの正体が
お嬢ちゃんだと分かった段階で
阿良々木くんは どうして
お嬢ちゃんの話を聞こうなんて
思ったんだい？
You should've ignored her and come straight to me when that happened.
その時点で お嬢ちゃんを
すっ飛ばして
僕のところに来るのが
本当だっただろうに
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Everyone hates someone at some point.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
生きてりゃ
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
誰かを憎むことくらい
あるだろうさ
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
I think I'll pass on getting killed.
殺されるのは そりゃ ご免だけれど
If looking up to Senjougahara is the reason Kanbaru hates me, I can forgive that.
神原が戦場ヶ原に
憧れてたっていうのが
僕を憎む理由だっていうのなら
別に許せるしさ
I see. Well, if that's what you've decided, then so be it.
（忍野）あっそ
まあ それが阿良々木くんの
決めたことなら
それで いいんだけれどね
I don't care. It's none of my business.
全然 構わないさ
僕の知ったことじゃない
Now then, Araragi-kun.
じゃあ 阿良々木くん
お嬢ちゃんに力 貸してあげなよ
Go help the young lady out.
Just so you know, once you go in, you can't come out until it's over.
言っとくけど 中に入ったら
事が終わるまで
もう出られないからね
The door won't open from the inside, no matter what.
内側からは絶対に扉
開かなくなっちゃうから
And of course, if anything does happen, neither I nor Shinobu-chan will come to save you.
もちろん 何があっても
僕や忍ちゃんが
助けに現れるなんてことは
ないからね
Don't forget that.
忘れないでね
（阿良々木）ああ
Right.
Sorry for the trouble.
世話かけるな
No worries.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（忍野）
いいよ
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
よお
Hi.
Sorry, Kanbaru!
神原 ごめん！
（阿良々木）
効いてる
Is it working?
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（阿良々木）
えっ 足…
She can use not only her left arm, but her legs too?!
使えるのは
左腕だけじゃないのか？
Not only does the Rainy Devil left arm want to attack me, but Kanbaru herself, too.
レイニー･デビルの
左腕だけじゃなく
神原本人も
僕を攻撃しようとしている！
無意識に神原は拒否しているんだ
Unconsciously, Kanbaru is rejecting it.
She's rejecting that her wish won't come true.
２つ目の願いが かなわないことを
Killed
Animation Number 259
That I won't be killed.
僕を殺さないことを
Kanbaru has no intention of giving up on Senjougahara.
神原は戦場ヶ原を諦める気がない
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Please, cut it off.
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（神原）
切り落としてくれ
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Destruction
Animation Number 263
I don't need this left arm...
こんな左手 いらない
（阿良々木）
なに バカなこと言ってんだ
What the hell are you talking about?
There's no way we can do that.
できるわけがないだろ
そんなこと
What about basketball?!
バスケットボールは
どうするんだよ
I tried to kill a person!
（神原）
私は人間一人を
殺そうとしたのだぞ
It's a small price to pay in comparison.
それくらい当然の代償だろう
い… いや 神原
Come on, Kanbaru. I'm telling you, I don't care about that.
僕は そんなこと
全然気にしてないって
If you're going to cut it off, I know a good way to do it.
（忍野）
切り落とすなら
いい方法があるよ
If you use Shinobu-chan's blade, it's possible to cut off that arm so fast you won't even feel it.
忍ちゃんのブレードなら
痛みを感じる暇もなく
Suruga Kanbaru
その左腕を
切断することが可能だろう
Suruga Kanbaru
Even with Shinobu-chan in her current state, cutting off a thin arm like that is a piece of cake.
今の忍ちゃんでも お嬢ちゃんの
細腕を切り落とすくらい
朝飯前だよ
Shut your mouth, Oshino!
黙ってろ！ 忍野
Hey, Kanbaru!
おい 神原
It's not something to worry so much about, is it?
そんな
思い詰めるようなことじゃないだろ
There's no reason for you to feel responsible at all.
お前が責任を感じることなんて
ちっともないんだ
The Monkey's Paw... no, this aberration called the Rainy Devil is what did this.
これは全部 猿の手… じゃない
レイニー･デビルとかいう怪異が
元凶で…
The aberration only granted her wish, didn't it?
怪異は願いを
かなえただけだろう？
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
She made the wish, and it granted it.
求められたから与えただけだろう
Wasn't it the same with Tsundere-chan?
ツンデレちゃんのときも
そうだったんじゃないのかな？
（阿良々木）うう…
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
I don't care, Araragi-senpai.
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（神原）
構わない 阿良々木先輩
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
You have to care! There's no way you can't!
（阿良々木）
構うよ
構わないわけないだろう
何 言ってんだよ
What are you saying?!
And what are you going to do about Senjougahara?
それに 戦場ヶ原のことは
どうするんだよ
I... want you and Senjougahara to...
僕は お前に戦場ヶ原と…
That's enough.
もう いい
I don't care anymore, not even about Senjougahara-senpai.
戦場ヶ原先輩のことも
もう いい
（阿良々木）あっ あ…
I don't care.
もう いいから　諦めるから
I give up, so...
（阿良々木）どわっ ぐわ…
憎い 憎い 憎い…
You can't.
（阿良々木）
お前じゃ ダメなんだよ
神原駿河(するが)！
Kanbaru Suruga!
HATE! HATE! HATE! HATE!
（雨がっぱ）憎い！ 憎い！
Hate
Animation Number 287
憎い！ 憎い！
Hate
Animation Number 287
かんば… ぐわっ
Voice
Speech
Animation Number 'none'
Can't keep any more
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Looks like you've been enjoying yourself.
（戦場ヶ原）
随分と
はしゃいでいるわね
Having fun without me, are you?
（戦場ヶ原）
私抜きで楽しそうね
阿良々木くん 不愉快だわ
How thoughtless, Araragi-kun.
S-Senjougahara....
せっ 戦場ヶ原…
Did Oshino use my phone?
（阿良々木）
忍野… 僕の携帯を使ったのか
Araragi-kun, you lied to me.
（戦場ヶ原）
阿良々木くん
私にウソをついたわね
You tricked me by saying you hit a telephone pole, and you hid everything about Kanbaru.
（戦場ヶ原）
電柱にぶつかったなんて
私をだまして
神原のことも秘密にして
Didn't we promise not to do that when we started going out?
つきあうとき
約束しなかったっけ？
Not to keep secrets like that from each other, no matter how small?
そういうことをするのは
なしにしようって
私たちは少なくとも
怪異のことに関して
互いに秘密を持たないって
あっ いや…
No, I...
I'll kill you 10,000 times over.
万死に値するわ
（阿良々木）ハッ
But really, Araragi-kun, it looks like you've already died 10,000 times or so...
でも まあ 阿良々木くん
既に１万回くらい
死んだあとみたいだし？
Maybe I'll forgive you just this once.
特別に許してあげようかしら
（阿良々木）あっ！
You weren't really stupid enough to think that if you died,
阿良々木くん
どうせ あなたのことだから
the entire problem would be solved, were you, Araragi-kun?
自分が死ねば全部解決するとか
間の抜けたことを
思っていたんじゃないかしら
Give me a break.
冗談じゃないわよ
If you died, I'd obviously do everything in my power to kill Kanbaru.
阿良々木くんが死んだら
私は どんな手を使ってでも
神原を殺すに決まっているじゃない
Araragi-kun, are you trying to turn me into a murderer?
阿良々木くん 私を
殺人犯にするつもり？
She saw right through it.
（阿良々木）
お見通しか
まったく 情の深い女だ
Really, she's so understanding...
What really disgusts me most, though, is that even if you didn't have that body,
（戦場ヶ原）
私が何より気に食わないのは
阿良々木くんが たとい
そんな体じゃなくとも
同じ行為に身を
投じていただろうということが
I know you would have thrown yourself at this problem in just the same way.
はっきりと分かってしまうことよ
（阿良々木）うう…
If you did these stupid things simply because you knew you could rely on your immortal body,
（戦場ヶ原）
不死身の体に おんぶにだっこで
こんなバカなことを
やっているのだったら
I would just tell you to do as you please.
どうぞ お好きなようにという
感じなのだけれど
But Araragi-kun, the way you just jump into these things like it's the obvious response... I just don't get it.
阿良々木くんときたら
当たり前みたいに
流れの まにまに
そんなありさまに なってしまって
もう さっぱりね
Well, be it a terrible burden, an unncecessary intrusion, an unasked favor,
Well, be it a terrible burden,
an unnecessary intrusion, an unasked favor,
Animation Number 343
まあ 大きな お世話も
余計な おせっかいも
ありがた迷惑も
it might not be too bad if it's you who's doing it, Araragi-kun.
阿良々木くんに されるなら
そんなに悪くはないのかも
しれないわ
（阿良々木）あ…
Let's say that one plan was to defeat the demon and make it impossible for the hidden part
（阿良々木）
僕が悪魔を圧倒し
神原の裏の願いの成就を
不可能にしてしまうのが
of Kanbaru's wish to be fulfilled...
１つの方策であるとすれば
but revealing to Senjougahara that Kanbaru really wanted to kill me, making it impossible
神原が僕を
殺そうとしているという事実を
戦場ヶ原に知らせることで
for the other side of her wish to be fulfilled was another plan, as well.
表の願いの成就を
不可能にしてしまうことも
また １つの方策
What's more, Senjougahara swore right in front of the demon that she'd kill Kanbaru if Kanbaru killed me.
まして今 戦場ヶ原は
僕が死んだら神原を殺すとまで
悪魔の目の前で宣誓した
It couldn't get away with feigning ignorance.
知らなかったでは済まされない
To the Rainy Devil, the decision had already been made.
レイニー･デビルにとって
状況は もう完全に
決定してしまったのだ
I can't believe you saw through all that, Oshino.
何て見透かしたまねをするんだ
忍野
You... even when compared to a demon, are one magnificent bastard.
お前は… お前は本当に
悪魔なんかよりも ずっと
とんでもないヤツだよな
Long time no see, Kanbaru.
神原 久しぶり
元気そうで何よりね
I'm glad you're well.
I love you, Senjougahara-senpai.
私は戦場ヶ原先輩が好きだ
I know.
そう　私は それほど
好きじゃないわ
I don't really love you.
Will you stay by my side despite that?
それでも そばに
いてくれるのかしら
Sorry I kept you waiting.
いっぱい待たせて
ごめんなさいね
Man, even being the fall guy has its good points.
（阿良々木）
まったく かませ犬も
いいところだった
It was like I had a comic role written just for me.
我ながら あつらえたような
三枚目を演じたものである
Even though I of all people should've known how greedy and what a sore loser Senjougahara Hitagi is.
戦場ヶ原ひたぎが
どれだけ強欲で
諦めの悪い女なのか
ということくらい
僕は とっくに
知っていたはずなのに
If it really was so important.
Animation Number 361
If it really was so important, there's no way she'd give up on it.
それが 本当に
大事なものだったなら
戦場ヶ原が
諦めるわけがないのに
Butting in.
大きな お世話
Being nosy.
余計な おせっかい ありがた迷惑
Doing unwelcome favors.
But, well...
しかし まあ
それでも何というか
How should I put it?
Both of them are really hard to deal with.
全くもって
どいつもこいつも 本当に
ひねくれてるよなあ
That's Deneb, Altair, Vega
the summer triangle that you pointed out.
Nii-chan! Come on, it's morning!
（火憐(かれん)）
兄ちゃん！ 朝だぞ こら
So remember
You gotta get up already!
（月火(つきひ)）
いいかげんに
起きないとダメだよ！
to look at the sky.
Come on!
（火憐）もう！
（月火）もう！
Come on!
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（阿良々木）ぎえ〜！
I finally found you, Altair,
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Mornin', Araragi-senpai.
though where are you, Vega?
（神原）
おはよう 阿良々木先輩
This is loneliness.
Araragi
Good morning, Kanbaru-san.
おはようございます
神原さん
Do you need something?
で 何か用なのか？
Senjougahara-senpai called this morning and asked me to come meet you.
今朝 戦場ヶ原先輩から
電話があって
I looked up from the pitch-dark world.
阿良々木先輩を
迎えに行くように
言われたのだ
あっ
かばんを持たせてくれ
Let me grab your bag.
The stars fell in the night sky, and
All right, let's go, Senpai!
さあ 行くぞ 先輩
（阿良々木）おう…
Hey, what about your club?
しかし お前
部活は いいのかよ？
Don't you have practice on Sundays?
日曜だって 練習は
あるはずだろう？
just when was it from?
ほら そろそろ
試験休みなんだから
The break before exams is coming, so you have to get serious.
That I, who ran after you,
気合入れていかないと
No, I can't play basketball anymore.
いや
バスケットボールは
was there.
もう できないのだ
It may be a bit early, but I'm quitting. It's really only half-done, after all.
（神原）
少し早いが引退だ
全てが
中途半端だったからな
Please heed my wish.
The demon left, but in the end my arm didn't go back to normal.
悪魔は去ったが
Don't be surprised.
結局 腕は
元には戻らなかったのだ
Listen
There's really no way I can keep playing basketball with my arm like it is.
いくらなんでも
この腕で
バスケットボールを
続けるわけには
to these feelings
いかないからな
But in any case, it is pretty powerful and easy to use.
でも まあ これはこれで
パワフルで 結構
使い勝手は
いいみたいだぞ
of mine.
Give my bag back, now.
（阿良々木）
僕のかばんを今すぐ返せ
Bakemonogatari
Monkey.
Suruga Monkey, Part Three
CONTINUED NEXT TIME
I'm Karen!
（火憐）火憐だぜ！
（月火）月火だよ！
I'm Tsukihi!
On the subject of Koyomi, he's more than just our brother.
暦といえば お兄ちゃんだけど
Bro, you mean?
（火憐）
兄ちゃんだね
Do you know about Sanninbou?
（月火）
三隣亡(さんりんぼう)って暦 知ってる？
Sanninbou?
（火憐）
三隣亡？
It's a certain date on which some believe building a house will cause a great fire,
（月火）
その日に家を建てたら
隣３軒まで巻き込む大火災が
起こるという
destroying three neighboring houses!
恐るべき暦なのだ
What a frightening belief!
（火憐）
恐るべき 怖い
As expected of the brother of the fire sisters!
（月火）
さすがファイヤーシスターズの
お兄ちゃん
Just as expected of our brother!
（火憐）
さすがファイヤーシスターズの
兄ちゃんだ
But check this out, it's a textbook method to get away with murder!
（月火）
でも これ 推理小説のトリックに
使えないかな？
What kind of recipe?
（火憐）
どんなふうに？
The criminal is one who uses Sanninbou!
（月火）
犯人は三隣亡の日に
家を建てたのだ
（火憐）
隣家の人を殺すために！
A license to kill!
With - or without - a reason!
（月火）あり？
（火憐）なし！
Postview quiz!
（月火）
過去編クイズ！
Postview?!
（火憐）
過去編かよ！
Last time Suruga Monkey Part Two!
（月火）
前回「するがモンキー 其ノ貮(そのに)」
Everyone knows!
（火憐）
みんな知ってる
Next time! Nadeko Snake, Part One!
Next Time
Nadeko Snake, Part One
（月火･火憐）
次回「なでこスネイク
其ノ壹(そのいち)」
That's Sen-chan's turn.
（月火）
あっ 千(せん)ちゃんの出番だね
Don't push it.
（火憐）
素になんなよ…